Yasaman Soleymanizadeh

Yalova, Turkey

Yasaman.soleymanizadeh@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/yasaman-soleymanizade https://github.com/soleymaniyasaman

(+90) 506-155-3977

SUMMARY

Developer with 3 years of experience implementing React, JavaScript, HTML/CSS to improve Front-end development technology in UI of single-page sites. Interested in developing complex solutions, creating responsive designs, possessing creative thinking. Prepared companies to develop goals and increased usage of projects by 70%

EXPERIENCE

May 2022 -

Present

Freelance Front-End Developer

- Edited existing codes to improve browser compatibility and mobile responsiveness.
- Led full redesign of the website with findings from customer segmentation, by using NextJs and TailwindCSS increasing website leads by 200%
- Increased daily traffic by 35% to 80% by redesigning existing websites to improve UX

Oct 2019 -Mar 2022

MOJ Secure e-commerce

Front-End Developer

- Created a FinTech platform (cryptocurrency exchange WebApp), both the admin dashboard panel and the user panel (from 0 to 100), growing revenues by 30%
- Developed a Know Your Customer (KYC) security clearance process for the cryptocurrency exchange using React-Step-Wizard
- Leveraged the real-time data provided by SocketIO, to reduce the time to reach data by 10 seconds
- Prepared the in-house UI library with usability components that saved over 100 hours of development time per month
- Negotiated with the core development team, back-end team, and designers in an agile software development environment to increase productivity by 25%
- Performed access 70% easier by transferring transactions to +15 tables and charts (ChartJs) with 90% details
- Formulated features to analyze and review incoming amounts in less than 1 second for instant buying and selling of currency
- Tracked and reported software defects and performance analysis using bug-tracking tools, and unit testing and resolved 90% of issues discovered

Dec 2018 – Oct 2019

AMA (Alaedin Media & Advertising)

Front-End Developer

- Developed a web application for a large mobile phone shopping mall with frameworks such as Next.Js and React (in a team of 4, scrum-based)
- Cooperated in each step of the product development process from choosing the framework to choosing the design pattern for features reaching over 250 user admins
- Designed and customized assessment forms for different customer stages that cut processing time by 30%
- Produced visual elements and charts of Web applications by translating UI/UX design wireframes into code, producing high quality markup using HTML5 and CSS3
- Collected SSR (Next.JS library) data, taught this to the team, reduced project execution time by 20%
- Trained a junior front—end developer on the team on React so could do 30% of the project coding

EDUCATION

Sep 2011 – Oct 2016

Bachelor of Electrical Engineering

Islamic Azad University| West Tehran Branch

• Major: Electrical and Electronic Engineering

SKILLS

- React.js, Next.js, Npm/Yarn Package Manager, Flux, Redux, Context, React Router, JavaScript/JSX, ES6/ES7, HTML5, TypeScript
- CSS3, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap, Material-UI/Design, SASS/LESS, Styled-Components, ESLint, Chart.js, Chart apex
- Swagger, Postman
- API design pattern(GraphQL Query Language& RESTful Web Services) and integrations
- real-time data provided by SocketIO
- Jest, Jasmine, Jenkins, Webpack, Babel
- Git version Controls, GitHub/GitLab, Jira
- Agile Methodologies, Scrum Methodologies